<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://opentrack.run/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://opentrack.run/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-07-09T16:46:32+01:00</updated><id>https://opentrack.run/</id><title type="html">OpenTrack – The complete competition management suite</title><subtitle>The complete competition management suite for athletics organisers. Our open cloud platform saves time for organisers and volunteers and makes it more fun for participants, helping the sport to grow.</subtitle><author><name>OpenTrack</name></author><entry><title type="html">Dark Blue is the colour</title><link href="https://opentrack.run/2017/12/04/varsityXC.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Dark Blue is the colour" /><published>2017-12-04T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-12-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://opentrack.run/2017/12/04/varsityXC</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://opentrack.run/2017/12/04/varsityXC.html">&lt;p&gt;Thames Hare and Hounds hosted the annual Varsity Match on Wimbledon Common. Nothing new in that, but this year we had splits from round 
the course relayed back to the club house. They and the finish line results were recorded using OpenTrack mobile phone technology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Thames course is a single lapper so unless you have a reasonable turn of speed spectating involves waiting for the athletes
to come back 40 minutes after the gun goes off. Using our mobile phone system we could track the pulsating men’s race as the lead switched from Cambridge to Oxford. The ladies race was more one sided but the individual leaders could be followed.  Despite a few teething problems, the test was a success and the results and splits are on our &lt;a href=&quot;https://data.opentrack.run/x/2017/GBR/varsityxc/event/&quot;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt;. We will be using the system again for the alumni race in a fortnight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://file.opentrack.run/img/2017/vmwinners-2017.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://file.opentrack.run/img/2017/vmwinners-2017.png&quot; alt=&quot;VM&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
The Victorious Teams&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Andy Weir</name></author><summary type="html">Thames Hare and Hounds hosted the annual Varsity Match on Wimbledon Common. Nothing new in that, but this year we had splits from round the course relayed back to the club house. They and the finish line results were recorded using OpenTrack mobile phone technology.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">One year comes to an end, 2018 is kicking off…</title><link href="https://opentrack.run/2017/11/28/County-XC-Champs-are-coming.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="One year comes to an end, 2018 is kicking off..." /><published>2017-11-28T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-11-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://opentrack.run/2017/11/28/County-XC-Champs-are-coming</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://opentrack.run/2017/11/28/County-XC-Champs-are-coming.html">&lt;p&gt;We have now opened entries for two county cross country championships. We wish the athletes from Surrey and Buckinghamshire 
the very best of luck.
They will be the first to use our refined entry process. Now, if you have previously entered using our system,
the screens quickly allow you to check your details, including EA number, choose your event and pay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://file.opentrack.run/img/2017/james_dorking1.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://file.opentrack.run/img/2017/james_dorking1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Reigate&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
The Leaders at Dorking 2 years ago&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Andy Weir</name></author><summary type="html">We have now opened entries for two county cross country championships. We wish the athletes from Surrey and Buckinghamshire the very best of luck. They will be the first to use our refined entry process. Now, if you have previously entered using our system, the screens quickly allow you to check your details, including EA number, choose your event and pay.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Athtech 2017…The 2nd Annual Athletics Data Conference</title><link href="https://opentrack.run/2017/10/19/athtech_2017.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Athtech 2017...The 2nd Annual Athletics Data Conference" /><published>2017-10-19T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2017-10-19T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://opentrack.run/2017/10/19/athtech_2017</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://opentrack.run/2017/10/19/athtech_2017.html">&lt;p&gt;Following the success of our inaugural data conference last year we were on the organising committee of Athtech 2017. Working with our friends from European Athletics, the W3C and the Algarve Athletics Federation we devised a 3 day &lt;a href=&quot;https://athtech.run/&quot;&gt;  agenda &lt;/a&gt; covering a variety of topics from data standards to results visualisation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether it was the agenda or the location near Faro, with 25 Deg C temperatures and blue skies, we do not know; but we doubled last years turn out. Despite Monarch Airlines going bust the day before, 35 delgates including 13 athletics federations met, worked together and discussed some of the big problems in athletics technology. OpenTrack, in the guise of Andy Robinson presented our &lt;a href=&quot;https://estonia.opentrack.run/&quot;&gt; Federation Management &lt;/a&gt;, competition management and data capture work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://file.opentrack.run/img/2017/athtech.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://file.opentrack.run/img/2017/athtechgdpr.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;GDPR Session&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GDPR Session&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other fascinating sessions included a presentation on GDPR (see photo) and a chance to try out athletics technology in practice on the local track. We have received good feedback on all the sessions from the morning run onwards and &lt;a href=&quot;https://drive.google.com/file/d/0B1SQhmuh1fT4U3lGWGZsb1NGaXM/view&quot;&gt; detailed minutes&lt;/a&gt; have been written. We are looking forward to Athech 2018, possibly in Northern Spain in the Autumn.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Andy Weir</name></author><summary type="html">Following the success of our inaugural data conference last year we were on the organising committee of Athtech 2017. Working with our friends from European Athletics, the W3C and the Algarve Athletics Federation we devised a 3 day agenda covering a variety of topics from data standards to results visualisation.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Cross Country Season kicks off with a bang</title><link href="https://opentrack.run/2017/10/19/SurreyLeague1-2017.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Cross Country Season kicks off with a bang" /><published>2017-10-19T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2017-10-19T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://opentrack.run/2017/10/19/SurreyLeague1-2017</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://opentrack.run/2017/10/19/SurreyLeague1-2017.html">&lt;p&gt;The surrey league is entering its 58th season and has grown into one of the largest and highest quality cross country leagues in the UK. The first fixtures of the 2017-2018 season were on two iconic courses: the beautiful and hilly Priory Park in Reigate and the home of cross country running at Wimbledon Common. Record turnouts in both men’s and women’s races meant the pressure was on to organise these prestigious events.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite their long history the Leagues have moved with the times and OpenTrack calculates the results and hosts the website. Team mangers enter the teams electronically either in advance or from the course on their mobile phones. The race organisers enter the times and finishing positions of the runners and the results appear on the site. Thanks to the hard working volunteer marshals and timekeepers we had most of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://surreyleague.org/&quot;&gt; results &lt;/a&gt; displayed well before 6pm, in time for their perusal in the pub. The official results were out in plenty of time for the Athletics Weekly deadline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://file.opentrack.run/img/2017/surreyleague1.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://file.opentrack.run/img/2017/surreyleague1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Reigate&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Leaders at Reigate&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have received a lot of positive feedback from individual athletes all the way up to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/SurreyCrossCountryLeague/&quot;&gt; League Secretary &lt;/a&gt; himself. As Thames boys we were even more pleased to see the Saltires win both fixtures and hence we are top of the Men’s and Women’s Leagues, for now. Get ready for Nov 11 when we will try and do it all again.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Andy Weir</name></author><summary type="html">The surrey league is entering its 58th season and has grown into one of the largest and highest quality cross country leagues in the UK. The first fixtures of the 2017-2018 season were on two iconic courses: the beautiful and hilly Priory Park in Reigate and the home of cross country running at Wimbledon Common. Record turnouts in both men’s and women’s races meant the pressure was on to organise these prestigious events.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Vilnius…European Athletics Congress in the rain</title><link href="https://opentrack.run/2017/10/19/European-Athletics-Congress.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Vilnius...European Athletics Congress in the rain" /><published>2017-10-19T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2017-10-19T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://opentrack.run/2017/10/19/European-Athletics-Congress</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://opentrack.run/2017/10/19/European-Athletics-Congress.html">&lt;p&gt;Straight after the Portuguese experience of Athtech in 25 deg C we flew to Vilnius for the European Athletics Congress. This biennial event is where the 51 federations meet to plan the next few years and discuss where the sport is going. We were assured the city is beautiful, but the 72 hours of continuous rain meant we didn’t see too much of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inside the convention centre we spoke in a 3 hour session on data with Nicolas, EA’s head of technology and Mirko the statistician from Tilastopaja. The session started with a warm introduction from Executive Board Member, Dobromir Karamarinov (pictured below), and we covered Data Capture, Federation Management and Competition Management. We even had time for an indoor cross country race to show off our timing solutions. The animation of the World Championships &lt;a href=&quot;https://data.opentrack.run/x/2017/GBR/wc/event/22/1/1/&quot;&gt;high jump &lt;/a&gt; opened people’s eyes to what can be done to bring field events alive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://file.opentrack.run/img/2017/dobromir.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://file.opentrack.run/img/2017/dobromir.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Vilnius Session&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dobromir opening the Data session in Vilnius&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the presentation we had several one to one meetings with the federations and attended the Congress Dinner with the stars of European and International Athletics from Lord Coe down.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Andy Weir</name></author><summary type="html">Straight after the Portuguese experience of Athtech in 25 deg C we flew to Vilnius for the European Athletics Congress. This biennial event is where the 51 federations meet to plan the next few years and discuss where the sport is going. We were assured the city is beautiful, but the 72 hours of continuous rain meant we didn’t see too much of it.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">DNA - the first match</title><link href="https://opentrack.run/2017/09/01/dna-first-match.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="DNA - the first match" /><published>2017-09-01T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2017-09-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://opentrack.run/2017/09/01/dna-first-match</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://opentrack.run/2017/09/01/dna-first-match.html">&lt;p&gt;This weekend sees the first ever &lt;i&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dynamic New Athletics&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/i&gt; matches hosted by European Athletics at Wimbledon Park.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Saturday 2nd September&lt;/strong&gt;: 14:30 - 17:30  &lt;em&gt;(completed)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sunday 3rd September&lt;/strong&gt;: 13:30 - 16:30 - sign in by 14:00&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://goo.gl/forms/obPi04eIVZRZfXjJ2&quot;&gt;Click here to sign up&lt;/a&gt;-&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;-
&lt;a href=&quot;http://file.opentrack.run/docs/2017/dna/dna_guide_v3.pdf&quot;&gt;Download full event guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a new format for team athletics competitions, being launched internationally next year. It includes many innovations to make an exciting and fun team competition, with many new wrinkles, and can be adapted to youth, club and university level easily.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://file.opentrack.run/img/2017/ladders.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image here&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://file.opentrack.run/docs/2017/dna/dna_guide_v3.pdf&quot;&gt;Click here&lt;/a&gt; for all the details of the meeting as a whole and the individual events within the program.  These are designed both to be fun and rewarding for the athletes, and also a great watch for spectators.  The event is going to be filmed, and the edited version shown at the European Athletics Conference next month, as they develop this new format for the sport.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://file.opentrack.run/img/2017/logo-eaa.png&quot; alt=&quot;European Athletics logo&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re looking for more athletes to come down on Sunday and do a fun session.   We need to create 6 club / composite teams on the day - each of which require between 4 and 6 athletes of each gender.  We’re offering £20 to the first 50 athletes to sign up (and come down).   &lt;a href=&quot;https://goo.gl/forms/obPi04eIVZRZfXjJ2&quot;&gt;Sign up here…&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each athlete should expect to do 2-3 events on the day, in the course of the program (although if you want a great session, you can do more!).  There is no need to go all-out and you can treat it as a fun group session, or a social “sports day”. The programme includes&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Men’s Javelin and Womens’ High and Long Jump, in an innovative knockout format.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Relays and paarlaufs&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;100 / 110 hurdles (lower heights to encourage participation)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;a “Mini-athlon” - a multi-events fitness challenge in 5 minutes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A handicapped distance medley relay to finish, so the first runner home wins the match&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, this is a fun and exciting new development for the sport with support from the very highest level.  It will be on the international stage in 2019 at the European Games.  England Athletics is following with interest too.  This gives you an opportunity to experience it and your feedback may influence how the sport develops.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also welcome spectators, officials, coaches and helpers.  Your feedback will help to shape the final events, at which GBR and others will compete in future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please do sign up, or (if you can bring some athletes or friends on the day) email Andy Robinson (andy@reportlab.com) or ben@bennoadcoaching.com.  Or give us a call in the morning on 07725 056175&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://goo.gl/forms/obPi04eIVZRZfXjJ2&quot;&gt;Click here to sign up&lt;/a&gt;  &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://file.opentrack.run/docs/2017/dna/dna_guide_v3.pdf&quot;&gt;Download full event guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Andy Robinson</name></author><summary type="html">This weekend sees the first ever Dynamic New Athletics matches hosted by European Athletics at Wimbledon Park.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Proposed county rule change</title><link href="https://opentrack.run/2017/07/03/county-rule-change.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Proposed county rule change" /><published>2017-07-03T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2017-07-03T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://opentrack.run/2017/07/03/county-rule-change</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://opentrack.run/2017/07/03/county-rule-change.html">&lt;p&gt;We’ve been asked to publicise a proposed rule change for county eligibility.  The deadline for comments is July 20th.  Please pass this on, and let Bedfordshire AAA know what you think by emailing &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:enquiries@leightonbuzzardac.co.uk&quot;&gt;enquiries@leightonbuzzardac.co.uk&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leighton Buzzard AC and Bedfordshire AAA have suggested that one be allowed to compete &lt;em&gt;having first claim membership of a club affiliated to that county&lt;/em&gt;, in addition to the current qualification by birth or residence. To actually proposa a rule change, they need messages of support from as many clubs and county associations as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please read their &lt;a href=&quot;http://file.opentrack.run/docs/2017/rule21change.pdf&quot;&gt;letter on the proposed Rule Change&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a nutshell, it’s a small county and most clubs are very near a boundary.  These clubs have little incentive to turn out as half their members may be over a border.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://file.opentrack.run/img/otwebsite/bedfordshire_portrait.png&quot; alt=&quot;Bedfordshire region&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seven of nine Bedfordshire clubs are near a county boundary&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re in support of this for two reasons.  First of all, it can only increase participation, encouraging clubs on county boundaries to turn out in force.  &lt;em&gt;We know this affects about half the clubs in Surrey&lt;/em&gt;. Secondly, it will reduce the administration burden, because it’s easy to check.   It exactly ticks our mission statement:  &lt;em&gt;save time for the volunteers, and help the sport to grow&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve helped six counties manage their entries and prepare for their championships this May, saving many man-days in the preparation process.  We hope to do the same for more counties next season, and we have a pretty good idea by now where time goes and what creates headaches.  The biggest remaining “time sink” was checking peoples’ England Athletics eligibility - and when you check this, you do find out the first claim club too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Club membership is generally well known.  We’re working to get it accepted that this is actually Open Data; we think everyone should be able to see who’s registered with which club, not just the membership secretary, because this (in addition to your age group) is the basic data which the sport needs to function.  In many countries, like Spain, or Estonia (&lt;a href=&quot;https://estonia.opentrack.run/&quot;&gt;which we manage&lt;/a&gt;), the federation web site shows who all the members of all the clubs are in a given season.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, if this rule was adopted, we could quickly assemble an open public registry of which clubs were affiliated with which counties; and we’d be able to “clear” the vast majority of athletes as eligible AS THEY ENTERED.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right now, when an athlete enters a county championships, we are forced to ask them “are you qualified by residence, or birth?”.  Many of them answer “both”, and we get into semantics because that option wasn’t available on the paper forms (apparently you’re supposed to say &lt;em&gt;birth&lt;/em&gt; if it’s both).  Verification is impractical because athletics officials cannot easily visit a registry office a thousand times, nor can they tell if someone borrows a postcode. We’re also uncomfortable collecting data on home addresses; it’s sensitive personal data, and the less of that we can collect, the better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://file.opentrack.run/img/otwebsite/products/entries/countychecks_square.png&quot; alt=&quot;OpenTrack recording data&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can simplify this a lot, if first claim club determined your eligibility&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a safe bet that 80% of the athletes entering will be a first claim member of a club in the county.  So that’s the default approach.  When we look someone up in the England Athletics API, we get back their first claim club.  So if this clears them to compete, we don’t even need to ask them about birth or residence. The scrutineers would only have to look at a small percentage of the athletes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have opinions on this, please let LBAC/Beds AAA know what you think by emailing &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:enquiries@leightonbuzzardac.co.uk&quot;&gt;enquiries@leightonbuzzardac.co.uk&lt;/a&gt;.   They need to demonstrate support from clubs and from counties if they are going to propose a rule change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;It’s a different gripe, but while we’re on the subject of the burden of checking entries, the other missing piece of the puzzle would be for the competition checker to tell us when peoples’ club memberships expired.  The current “three month grace period” means that the Competition Checker is basically lying to us in April, May and June, just when we need it most. It lets anyone challenge things and say “my club secretary will pay by June, honest!”  If the competition checker was clear on whether you had expired on 31st March 2017, or were paid until 31st March 2018, we’d all be able to exercise common sense.  Maybe a few athletes could be on a “watch list” and told they need to pay before the championships date, but most could be unambiguously cleared to compete without human intervention.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Andy Robinson
Managing Director, OpenTrack
9th July 2017&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Andy Robinson</name></author><summary type="html">We’ve been asked to publicise a proposed rule change for county eligibility. The deadline for comments is July 20th. Please pass this on, and let Bedfordshire AAA know what you think by emailing enquiries@leightonbuzzardac.co.uk.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Midsummer Frolics by Spankers Hill Wood</title><link href="https://opentrack.run/2017/06/15/midsummer-frolics.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Midsummer Frolics by Spankers Hill Wood" /><published>2017-06-15T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2017-06-15T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://opentrack.run/2017/06/15/midsummer-frolics</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://opentrack.run/2017/06/15/midsummer-frolics.html">&lt;p&gt;Thames Parkland Relays saw 100 teams compete on a beautiful evening in Richmond Park. The course is a classic, each 2.8 mile leg going round Spankers Hill wood, past the ballot school, up the Queen’s Ride and back home via Penn Ponds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Relays are a lot of fun, however they are horrific to organise and calculate the results. The handovers are a “zoo” On leg 1, 200 athletes handed over to each other within a few minutes, whilst officials tried to record the melee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://file.opentrack.run/img/2017/andy_greenleaf.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://file.opentrack.run/img/2017/andy_greenleaf.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Andy Greenleaf running&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Andy Greenleaf recorded the fastest leg of the day&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OpenTrack took the entries which sold out within two weeks and debuted our new relay team selection module. Team captains could select the members of their pre-entered teams on the night, or even change the order in the park if the 18:10 from Clapham was delayed. On the results side, we set up 2 recording teams using our mobile phone app with a paper and pen back up. The accuracy was remarkable and having the names and leg order stored electronically meant we could announce the &lt;a href=&quot;https://opentrack.info/c/2017parklandrelays/relay/finish/&quot;&gt;results&lt;/a&gt; in the pub well before last orders. If you are interested in our relay solutions please do get in touch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the day Thames won overall for men and women and also the vets men. A strong trio of Hercules Women won the vets prize. Nottingham University Old Boys kept up their strong tradition in this event with a second place overall and the fastest leg of the day from Andy Greenleaf (pictured). Though clearly it was the NOBs second leg runner that made the difference.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Andy Weir</name></author><summary type="html">Thames Parkland Relays saw 100 teams compete on a beautiful evening in Richmond Park. The course is a classic, each 2.8 mile leg going round Spankers Hill wood, past the ballot school, up the Queen’s Ride and back home via Penn Ponds.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">No chance to breathe, onto Night of the 10,000m PB’s</title><link href="https://opentrack.run/2017/05/22/No-chance-for-a-breath.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="No chance to breathe, onto Night of the 10,000m PB’s" /><published>2017-05-22T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2017-05-22T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://opentrack.run/2017/05/22/No%20chance%20for%20a%20breath</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://opentrack.run/2017/05/22/No-chance-for-a-breath.html">&lt;p&gt;Just because we are gluttons for punishment, one week after the county champs we got involved in probably the most exciting event currently on the British Athletics Calendar. The Night of the 10,000m PB’s is part athletics fest, including the UKA champs, part beer festival and 100% fun. 7,000 fans turned up including Seb Coe and Paula Radcliffe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://file.opentrack.run/img/2017/ten_thousand_PB1.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://file.opentrack.run/img/2017/ten_thousand_PB1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;10,000m PB race&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beth Potter (r) won the women’s title. (Photograph: Steve O’Sullivan)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We took the entries and worked with the tireless promoter Ben Pochee on the constantly changing race line up. We think we added bit of colour to the programme as we added club details, Pb’s and targets from our database. However, the big test for us was the live results….and they worked. As soon as the awesome photofinisher timing team, including Don Anderson and the indefatigable Jeanne Coker, had verified the results they were automatically on our website.  &lt;a href=&quot;https://entries.opentrack.run/2017/not/&quot;&gt; entries.opentrack.run &lt;/a&gt;  has never had so much traffic. It was also a vital step on our work with EA on the data capture project.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Andy Weir</name></author><summary type="html">Just because we are gluttons for punishment, one week after the county champs we got involved in probably the most exciting event currently on the British Athletics Calendar. The Night of the 10,000m PB’s is part athletics fest, including the UKA champs, part beer festival and 100% fun. 7,000 fans turned up including Seb Coe and Paula Radcliffe.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Spring is in the air, and it can only mean one thing…the County Championships</title><link href="https://opentrack.run/2017/05/17/Spring-is-in-the-air.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Spring is in the air, and it can only mean one thing...the County Championships" /><published>2017-05-17T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2017-05-17T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://opentrack.run/2017/05/17/Spring%20is%20in%20the%20air</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://opentrack.run/2017/05/17/Spring-is-in-the-air.html">&lt;p&gt;We worked with six counties this year in the lead up to their biggest events of the year. More than 3,000 athletes entered through our system; which showed itself up to the task. More importantly, hundreds of volunteer-hours were saved across the country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The biggest boon for the organisers was how we helped with the data. We offered automatic field cards, seeding lists, programme generation and even race number printing. The athletes loved their unique numbers; they even had their events and start-times listed on the bottom - no excuses for being late.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have a look for yourself &lt;a href=&quot;https://entries.opentrack.run&quot;&gt; on our entries site &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Andy Weir</name></author><summary type="html">We worked with six counties this year in the lead up to their biggest events of the year. More than 3,000 athletes entered through our system; which showed itself up to the task. More importantly, hundreds of volunteer-hours were saved across the country.</summary></entry></feed>